





https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikitamokashi-kale



Soft Skills

- Aspen Hysys (Intermediate)
- Pro-II (Intermediate)
- FlareNet (Intermediate)
- HTRI (Intermediate)
- Pipenet (Intermediate)
- MS Projects (Intermediate)
- AutoCAD (Intermediate)
- MS office (Advanced)
- Bluebeam Revu (Advanced)
- MySep (Intermediate)

Core Competencies

- Process Engineering
- Design and Development
- Project management and Coordination
- Team management

Nikita Mokashi

Professional Process Engineer with excellent technical, analytical, problem-solving and communication skills combined with strong process engineering and multi-discipline base, demonstrated by 9+ years of experience in basic and detailed design of plants.

Familiar with Gas Treatment, Ethylene technology, LNG Regasification, Fertilizers technology. International experience in commissioning of plant.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Process Engineer

Technip Energies, Abu Dhabi, UAE | 07/2022 - Present

- Working on detailed engineering of Sour Gas Processing Plant
- Developed Process Flow Diagram (PFD), Piping and Instrumentation Diagram (P&ID)
- Performed two phase and three phase gas-liquid separator sizing
- Safety Valve Scenario Identification, Calculations using API 520/521,
 ASME B 31.5 & Section VIII standards and Datasheet preparation
- Supported the commercial department for preparing technical proposals

Senior Process Engineer

Technip Energies, Mumbai, India | 07/2018 - 02/2022

- Worked on Basic and Detailed engineering of Ethylene (Liquid and Gas Cracker), VGO Hydrotreating Plant and LNG Regasification Plant
- Handled various process activities for Process Design Packages (PDPs), Front-End Engineering Design (FEED) and EPC projects.
- Worked as Area/Unit lead for various projects within the team
- Prepared Process Design Basis / Philosophies
- Prepared Heat and Material Balance (HMB) reports
- Developed Process Flow Diagram (PFD), Piping and Instrumentation Diagram (P&ID), Material Selection Diagram (MSD)
- Pump Hydraulics and Line Hydraulics Calculations
- Prepared Process Datasheets and Instrument Datasheets
- Prepared Cause & Effect (C&E) Matrix and Control logic, Line List
- Interface coordination with client and multi-disciplinary teams
- Prepared start-up and operating manuals
- Participated in HAZOP study of Plant with Client and Internal team
- Ensuring all HS&E standards for preparation of process deliverables
- Trained junior engineers in the use of process tools

Process Engineer

Shroff Engineering Consultants. Mumbai. India | 01/2017 - 06/2018

- Detailed Engineering of DMPAT, Chlorination and Specialty Chemicals Plant
- Discussion and Interface with vendors for evaluation of technical quotation of process equipment
- Formulated technical bid evaluation report and Recommendation
- Participated in 3D model review, P&ID review, Piping Isometric review
- Communicated effectively with Client, answering questions and concerns, Supported engineering contractors during design and construction phase
- Supervised Vendor equipment Inspection, Vendor drawing review/approval
- Participated in Software FAT for Control Logic Testing of Plant

Strengths

- Flexible
- Detail and Result Oriented
- Quick learner
- Time Management

Social Activities

- Conducted Educational camp in Rural part of India
- Active member of Zep Pratishthan (NGO)

Process Engineer

Armaco Chemical Process Systems, Mumbai, India | 07/2014 - 01/2017

- Participated in commissioning of Drilling Starch Plant
- Optimized and improved existing design of Phosphoric Acid, Single superphosphate and Di-calcium phosphate plants
- Generated new technology for Phosphoric Acid plant by Hemihydrate Process
- Estimated Man-hour calculation for various projects, costing of project

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering – Chemical

S.S. Jondhale College of Engineering, Mumbai, Result- 79.73%

Higher Secondary

R.J. College, Mumbai, Result- 84.50%

PROJECTS

Abu Dhabi National Oil Company (ADNOC), Abu Dhabi, UAE

- Front end engineering (FEED) of Hail & Ghasha Development and CO2 Recovery Plant – Handled Sour gas Inlet facility area, Sour Offgas and Sweet gas Compression area, CO2 recovery unit
- Basic engineering Design for Energy Optimization schemes for Ruwais Refinery

ExxonMobil Chemical Company, China

 Process Design Package for Ethylene Plant (Liquid Cracker) -Handled Quench and Cracked gas compression area

Essar Bulk Terminal Ltd, India

 Detailed engineering of LNG Regasification Plant – Handled Boil Off gas compression area

Chevron Philips Chemical Company, Texas

 Process Design Package for Ethylene Plant (Gas Cracker) – Handled Cold Fractionation area

Bharat Petroleum (BPCL), India

• Basic engineering of VGO Hydrotreater Plant

DuPont de Nemours, Inc.

PSV and Flare Study for Sabine River Ethylene Plant

United Phosphorus Ltd, India

Detailed Engineering of DMPAT Plant

Localline LLC, Oman

• Detailed Engineering of Drilling Starch Plant

ACHIVEMENTS

- Awarded in recognition of <u>Exceptional Performance and Delivery against</u> <u>schedule</u> in Technip Energies
- Awarded for <u>Debutante of the year 2017</u> in Shroff Engineering Consultant
- Ranked 5th in Bachelor of Chemical Engineering in University of Mumbai

01 November 2023